[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "The phrase ‘sine die’ means-",
    "options": ["half-heartedly", "doubtfully", "fixed", "uncertain"],
    "answer": "doubtfully"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Fill in the gap: Birds fly ___ in the sky.",
    "options": ["random", "at large", "at a stitch", "are long"],
    "answer": "are long"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Who is the author of ‘Jane Eyre’?",
    "options": [
      "Charlotte Bronte",
      "Emily Bronte",
      "Jane Austen",
      "Mary Shelley"
    ],
    "answer": "Charlotte Bronte"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The most famous romantic poet of English literature is-",
    "options": [
      "John Dryden",
      "Alexander Pope",
      "William Wordsworth",
      "T. S. Eliot"
    ],
    "answer": "William Wordsworth"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Identify the correct synonym for the word ‘magnanimous’.",
    "options": ["unkind", "generous", "revengeful", "friendly"],
    "answer": "generous"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which gender is the word ‘orphan’?",
    "options": ["neuter", "feminine", "common", "masculine"],
    "answer": "common"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Who wrote the play ‘The Way of the World’?",
    "options": [
      "William Shakespeare",
      "William Congreve",
      "Ben Jonson",
      "Oscar Wilde"
    ],
    "answer": "William Congreve"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "“Better to reign in Hell, than serve in Heav’n.”-Who wrote this?",
    "options": [
      "Geoffrey Chaucer",
      "Christopher Marlowe",
      "John Milton",
      "P. B. Shelley"
    ],
    "answer": "John Milton"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Who is not an Irish Writer?",
    "options": [
      "Oscar Wilde",
      "James Joyce",
      "Jonathan Swift",
      "D. H. Lawrence"
    ],
    "answer": "D. H. Lawrence"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "‘A herd of cattle is passing’. The underlined word is a/an-",
    "options": ["adverb", "adjective", "collective noun", "abstract noun"],
    "answer": "collective noun"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "What is the adjective form of the word ‘people’?",
    "options": ["populous", "popular", "popularity", "popularize"],
    "answer": "populous"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "A speech full of too many words is-",
    "options": [
      "a big speech",
      "maiden speech",
      "a verbose speech",
      "an unimportant speech"
    ],
    "answer": "a verbose speech"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Who is the poet of the poem ‘Ozymandias’?",
    "options": [
      "P. B. Shelley",
      "William Wordsworth",
      "S. T. Coleridge",
      "John Keats"
    ],
    "answer": "P. B. Shelley"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "‘Moby Dick’, a novel, was written by-",
    "options": [
      "Herman Melville",
      "Nathaniel Hawthorne",
      "Mark Twain",
      "William Faulkner"
    ],
    "answer": "Herman Melville"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "“if Winter comes, can Spring be far behind?”- Who wrote this?",
    "options": [
      "William Blake",
      "S. T. Coleridge",
      "Lord Byron",
      "P. B. Shelley"
    ],
    "answer": "P. B. Shelley"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "O’ Henry was from-",
    "options": ["Canada", "America", "England", "Ireland"],
    "answer": "America"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "‘He contemplated marrying his cousin’. Here ‘marrying’ is a/an-",
    "options": ["present participle", "gerund", "verb", "infinitive"],
    "answer": "gerund"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "‘No Second Troy’ is a-",
    "options": ["short story", "novel", "poem", "drama"],
    "answer": "poem"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Who is not a modern poet?",
    "options": ["W. B. Yeats", "W. H. Auden", "John Keats", "T. S. Eliot"],
    "answer": "John Keats"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel ‘The God of Small Things’?",
    "options": [
      "Thomas Hardy",
      "Jhumpa Lahiri",
      "R. K. Narayan",
      "Arundhati Roy"
    ],
    "answer": "Arundhati Roy"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Which of the following novels is not written by an English writer?",
    "options": [
      "A Passage to India",
      "Sons and Lovers",
      "One Hundred Years of Solitude",
      "Pride and Prejudice"
    ],
    "answer": "One Hundred Years of Solitude"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Where is the setting of the play ‘Hamlet’?",
    "options": ["England", "Italy", "France", "Denmark"],
    "answer": "Denmark"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "The word ‘to genuflect’ means-",
    "options": [
      "to be genuine",
      "to reflect",
      "to bend the knee",
      "to be flexible"
    ],
    "answer": "to bend the knee"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Fill in the blank: ‘She went to New Market ___’.",
    "options": ["on foot", "on feet", "by foot", "by walking"],
    "answer": "on foot"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Identify the word which is spelt incorrectly:",
    "options": ["fluctuation", "remission", "ocassion", "decision"],
    "answer": "ocassion"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Change the voice: ‘Nobody trusts a traitor’.",
    "options": [
      "A traitor is trusted",
      "A traitor should not be trusted",
      "Everybody hates a traitor",
      "A traitor is not trusted by anybody"
    ],
    "answer": "A traitor is not trusted by anybody"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Choose the right form of verb: ‘It is high time we (act) on the matter.’",
    "options": ["are acting", "acted", "have acted", "could act"],
    "answer": "acted"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "What is the noun form of the word ‘laugh’?",
    "options": ["laughing", "laughable", "laughter", "laughingly"],
    "answer": "laughter"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "What kind of play is ‘Julius Ceasar’?",
    "options": ["romantic", "anti-romantic", "comedy", "historical"],
    "answer": "historical"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Do you have any money __ you? Fill in the blank with appropriate preposition:",
    "options": ["to", "over", "in", "on"],
    "answer": "on"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "What is the antonym for the word ‘deformation’?",
    "options": ["distortion", "contortion", "wholeness", "disfigurement"],
    "answer": "wholeness"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Words inscribed on a tomb is an-",
    "options": ["epitome", "epithet", "episode", "epitaph"],
    "answer": "epitaph"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "The phrase ‘dog days’ means-",
    "options": [
      "hot weather",
      "cold shower",
      "rain-soaked streets",
      "ice storm"
    ],
    "answer": "hot weather"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "__ was both a poet and a painter.",
    "options": ["John Keats", "Spenser", "William Blake", "John Donne"],
    "answer": "William Blake"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Identify the correct sentence:",
    "options": [
      "The girl burst out tears",
      "The girl burst into tears",
      "The girl burst with tears",
      "The girl bursted out tears"
    ],
    "answer": "The girl burst into tears"
  }
]
